{
  "Week1": [
    {
      "question": "According to Max Weber, how would you define an organization?",
      "options": [
        "A random gathering of individuals",
        "A social entity that is rationally organized and coordinated to achieve specific goals and objectives",
        "A group of people with similar interests",
        "A chaotic assembly of people",
        "A natural formation of individuals"
      ],
      "answer": "A social entity that is rationally organized and coordinated to achieve specific goals and objectives"
    },
    {
      "question": "What was the key focus of the Hawthorne Studies?",
      "options": [
        "Analyzing time and motion in the workplace",
        "Identifying the one best way to perform tasks",
        "Examining the impact of lighting on worker productivity",
        "Standardizing work processes for increased efficiency",
        "Assessing individual competencies in a team setting"
      ],
      "answer": "Examining the impact of lighting on worker productivity"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the common theme in both Max Weber's and Chester Barnard's definitions of an organization?",
      "options": [
        "Anarchy and chaos",
        "Rational organization and coordination",
        "Isolation and individualism",
        "Spontaneous collaboration",
        "Random interactions"
      ],
      "answer": "Rational organization and coordination"
    },
    {
      "question": "How does Kurt Lewin's model define an individual's behavior?",
      "options": [
        "A random set of actions",
        "A pre-determined set of responses",
        "A function of the person (P) and their environment (E)",
        "An isolated occurrence",
        "A developmental change"
      ],
      "answer": "A function of the person (P) and their environment (E)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following gives an accurate definition of 'behavior'?",
      "options": [
        "Exclusively as developmental changes",
        "Internally coordinated responses to external stimuli",
        "Random and unpredictable actions",
        "Responses easily understood as developmental changes",
        "Coordinated responses excluding external stimuli"
      ],
      "answer": "Internally coordinated responses to external stimuli"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Kurt Lewin's model, what does the environment (E) include?",
      "options": [
        "Only physical surroundings",
        "Only social surroundings",
        "Both physical and social surroundings",
        "History and personality",
        "Isolated stimuli"
      ],
      "answer": "Both physical and social surroundings"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which key principles are associated with Frederick W. Taylor's Scientific Management?",
      "options": [
        "Creative improvisation and task diversity",
        "Standardization, and One Best Way",
        "Unpredictable work processes and tools",
        "Variation and adaptability in task execution",
        "Identifying multiple methods for each task"
      ],
      "answer": "Standardization, and One Best Way"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is/are NOT an issue of the modern day workplace?",
      "options": ["1 and 3", "2 only", "2 and 4", "3 only"],
      "answer": "2 only"
    },
    {
      "question": "Individual differences does NOT refer to which one of the following?",
      "options": [
        "Traits",
        "Cultural features",
        "Contributions",
        "Behavioral characteristics",
        "Demographic characteristics"
      ],
      "answer": "Contributions"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the significance of acknowledging individual differences in the context of managing competencies?",
      "options": [
        "It is unrelated to competency management strategies.",
        "It serves as the first step in managing one's own and subordinate's competencies.",
        "Acknowledging individual differences hinders effective competency assessment.",
        "It is essential only for self-competency, not for general competency.",
        "Individual differences have no impact on professional effectiveness."
      ],
      "answer": "It serves as the first step in managing one's own and subordinate's competencies."
    }
  ],
  "Week2": [
    {
      "question": "Workforce diversity means similarities and differences among employees in terms of age, cultural background, physical abilities and disabilities, race, religion, gender, and sexual orientation.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "Diversity makes the workforce homogeneous.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "answer": "False"
    },
    {
      "question": "Diversity at the workplace is important solely because it is a legal concern.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "answer": "False"
    },
    {
      "question": "One effective diversity management strategy is to recruit people from different genders to showcase a diverse team.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "answer": "False"
    },
    {
      "question": "A multicultural organization can be defined as one that 'Reflects the contributions and interests of diverse cultural and social groups in its mission, operations, and product or service'.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which one of the following is an individual approach to manage diversity?",
      "options": [
        "Those who may not think they need to learn about diversity can refrain from participating in diversity initiatives",
        "Communicating better",
        "Developing hard-to-change and strong views about other communities",
        "Cultivating strong in-group feelings for member of one’s own community",
        "Trying to understand others from your own experiences"
      ],
      "answer": "Communicating better"
    },
    {
      "question": "One of the ways organizations can foster diversity is:",
      "options": [
        "Providing a trusted counselor, coach or advisor who provides advice and assistance",
        "One type of group can be trained for an entry-level skill or how to more effectively do their existing job",
        "Keeping family worries away from mind once one enters the workplace",
        "Using general aptitude tests as the only basis for selection",
        "Fixed time schedule for everyone"
      ],
      "answer": "Providing a trusted counselor, coach or advisor who provides advice and assistance"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is true for deep-level diversity?",
      "options": [
        "Observable attributes and characteristics of individuals that are readily apparent, typically at first glance",
        "May not necessarily reflect an individual's identity, experiences, or perspectives",
        "It is related to race and ethnicity, gender, age etc.",
        "It is related to abilities, language, and religion",
        "It is related to values, attitudes, experiences, skills and knowledge"
      ],
      "answer": "It is related to values, attitudes, experiences, skills and knowledge"
    },
    {
      "question": "Diversity is called a double-edged sword because:",
      "options": [
        "It is desirable but no one is interested",
        "It is legal but people don’t believe in the need for it",
        "It is a modern day concern which is superficially dealt with",
        "It has great advantages for the organization like better decisions and enhanced learning and growth and at the same time it can lead to inter-group conflicts",
        "It is a hassle-free way to get away with conflicts"
      ],
      "answer": "It has great advantages for the organization like better decisions and enhanced learning and growth and at the same time it can lead to inter-group conflicts"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following can be related to neurodiversity?",
      "options": [
        "A random gathering of individuals",
        "Promotes the exclusion of neurological differences for better team performance",
        "A group of people with similar",
        "A chaotic assembly of people",
        "A natural formation of individuals"
      ],
      "answer": "A group of people with similar It celebrates the natural diversity of neurological differences in human beings"
    }
  ],
  "Week3": [
    {
      "question": "A process by which individuals organize and interpret their _______ impressions in order to give meaning to their environment is called perception.",
      "options": [
        "Perceptual",
        "Voluntary",
        "Involuntary",
        "Awkward",
        "Sensory"
      ],
      "answer": "Sensory"
    },
    {
      "question": "Self-concept can be best described in terms an individual’s:",
      "options": [
        "Self-esteem",
        "Self-sabotage",
        "Self-evaluations",
        "In-group",
        "Surroundings"
      ],
      "answer": "Self-evaluations"
    },
    {
      "question": "Self-concept complexity refers to:",
      "options": [
        "The degree to which the individual’s identities require similar personal attributes",
        "The degree to which an individual’s self-concept is clear",
        "Distinct roles or identities individuals perceive about themselves",
        "The degree to which the individual’s identities require dissimilar personal attributes",
        "Confidently defined, and stable identities"
      ],
      "answer": "Distinct roles or identities individuals perceive about themselves"
    },
    {
      "question": "Inherent motivation to have a positive self-concept is called:",
      "options": [
        "Self-motivation",
        "Self-enhancement",
        "Self-concepts",
        "Self-glorification",
        "self-clarity"
      ],
      "answer": "Self-enhancement"
    },
    {
      "question": "Factors in the perceiver which influences perception are:",
      "options": [
        "Experience, expectations and exactness",
        "Sounds, size and background",
        "Time and work setting",
        "Attitudes, motives and expectations",
        "Interests, novelty and similarity"
      ],
      "answer": "Attitudes, motives and expectations"
    },
    {
      "question": "Stereotypes are formed through: i) Shared beliefs across Society ii) Fact finding iii) Distorted truth iv) High status in society v) Media and Cultural Influence",
      "options": [
        "i, ii and iii",
        "iii, iv and v",
        "i, iii, and v",
        "iii only",
        "iii and v"
      ],
      "answer": "i, iii, and v"
    },
    {
      "question": "The thinking that all Indians have similar attitudes and characteristics refer to the process of:",
      "options": [
        "Categorization",
        "Homogenization",
        "Specification",
        "Differentiation",
        "Unification"
      ],
      "answer": "Homogenization"
    },
    {
      "question": "Overemphasis on internal causes for a behavior is ________.",
      "options": [
        "Self-serving bias",
        "Correspondence bias",
        "Distinctiveness",
        "Consensus",
        "Consistency"
      ],
      "answer": "Correspondence bias"
    },
    {
      "question": "After receiving high praise for her exceptional presentation skills, colleagues automatically assumed Sarah was also proficient in project management and leadership also. Here, the assumptions can be termed as:",
      "options": [
        "Horn effect",
        "Stereotype",
        "Recency effect",
        "Halo effect",
        "False consensus effect"
      ],
      "answer": "Halo effect"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the Jo-Hari window technique, the blind area represents aspects of a person:",
      "options": [
        "Not known to anyone",
        "Not known to the person themselves but known to others",
        "Not known to others",
        "Neither known to the person nor to others",
        "Known to all but not discussed"
      ],
      "answer": "Not known to the person themselves but known to others"
    }
  ],
  "Week4": [
    {
      "question": "Inconsistencies between the emotions people feel and the emotions they project is called:",
      "options": [
        "Emotional intelligence",
        "Cognitive dissonance",
        "Emotional labor",
        "Emotional dissonance",
        "Affect"
      ],
      "answer": "Emotional dissonance"
    },
    {
      "question": "James-Lange theory of emotion says that:",
      "options": [
        "Emotional experience is a reaction to bodily events",
        "Physiological arousal and emotional experience are produced simultaneously",
        "Emotions’ interpretations are based on cues in the environment",
        "Emotion is personality dependent",
        "Emotions are uncontrollable reactions to others’ behavior"
      ],
      "answer": "Emotional experience is a reaction to bodily events"
    },
    {
      "question": "_________ stressors are related with workload whereas ________ stressors keep you from reaching your goals.",
      "options": [
        "Negative, Positive",
        "Hindrance, Challenge",
        "Compensatory, Hindrance",
        "Challenge, Hindrance",
        "Chronic, Acute"
      ],
      "answer": "Challenge, Hindrance"
    },
    {
      "question": "A set of skills that to contribute to the accurate appraisal and expression of emotion in oneself and in others, the effective regulation of emotion in self and others is:",
      "options": [
        "Facial-feedback",
        "Emotional intelligence",
        "Facial affect program",
        "Emotional labor",
        "Mood dependent behavior"
      ],
      "answer": "Emotional intelligence"
    },
    {
      "question": "An unpleasant psychological process that occurs in response to environmental pressures is __________.",
      "options": [
        "Emotional labor",
        "Anxiety",
        "Breakdown",
        "Burnout",
        "Stress"
      ],
      "answer": "Stress"
    },
    {
      "question": "The symptoms of stress can be categorized broadly as:",
      "options": [
        "Physiological, psychological, behavioral",
        "Behavioral, emotional and cognitive",
        "Physiological, scientific and behavioral",
        "Psychosocial, economic and behavioral",
        "Psychological, emotional and physiological"
      ],
      "answer": "Physiological, psychological, behavioral"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following measures can be taken at an individual level for managing stress?",
      "options": [
        "Improved employee selection and job placement",
        "Training",
        "Redesign of jobs",
        "Increased employee involvement",
        "Expanded social support networks"
      ],
      "answer": "Expanded social support networks"
    },
    {
      "question": "When people behave in ways that threaten the organization, it is called ________?",
      "options": [
        "Differentiated behavior",
        "Cooperative behavior",
        "Deviant behavior",
        "Dissonance",
        "Democratic behavior"
      ],
      "answer": "Deviant behavior"
    },
    {
      "question": "One of the techniques of emotion regulation can be:",
      "options": [
        "Thinking about more unpleasant things",
        "Suppressing one’s opinions",
        "Reappraising the situation",
        "Distancing from the situation and people",
        "Withdrawing from speaking"
      ],
      "answer": "Reappraising the situation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Negative affectivity is ______ for the organization because it can lead to _____ :",
      "options": [
        "Useful, employee involvement",
        "Difficult, diversity",
        "Useful, ideas",
        "Harmful, safety issues",
        "Acceptable, creativity"
      ],
      "answer": "Harmful, safety issues"
    }
  ],
  "Week5": [
    {
      "question": "What is a key motivator for individuals in shaping their self-concept within an organizational context?",
      "options": [
        "Feeling undervalued",
        "External recognition only",
        "Desire to feel valued",
        "Fearing failure",
        "Strict adherence to situational factors"
      ],
      "answer": "Desire to feel valued"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which concept relates to a person's general belief about their control over life events?",
      "options": [
        "Self-esteem",
        "Self-efficacy",
        "Motivation levels",
        "Locus of control",
        "Role perceptions"
      ],
      "answer": "Locus of control"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which dimension of the Big Five Model refers to an individual's measure of reliability and includes traits like responsibility and organization?",
      "options": [
        "Extraversion",
        "Agreeableness",
        "Conscientiousness",
        "Emotional stability",
        "Openness to experience"
      ],
      "answer": "Conscientiousness"
    },
    {
      "question": "According to Freud, which component of the psyche operates on the reality principle and seeks to balance the conflicting demands of the id and superego?",
      "options": ["Id", "Ego", "Superego", "Conscience", "Emotion"],
      "answer": "Ego"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which method of assessing personality involves interpreting responses to ambiguous stimuli to reveal aspects of an individual's personality?",
      "options": [
        "Behavioral observations",
        "Self-report inventories",
        "Trait theories",
        "Interviews",
        "Projective tests"
      ],
      "answer": "Projective tests"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following characteristics is typically associated with Type A personalities?",
      "options": [
        "Relaxed, laid-back, and patient",
        "Tolerant, adaptive, and creative",
        "Highly competitive, assertive, and time-conscious",
        "Less focused on achievement and ambition",
        "More flexible and less prone to stress"
      ],
      "answer": "Highly competitive, assertive, and time-conscious"
    },
    {
      "question": "The Big Five Inventory (BFI) assesses personality by measuring which broad dimensions of personality?",
      "options": [
        "Openness, Honesty, Assertiveness, Timeliness, Emotional stability",
        "Attentiveness, Compassion, Extroversion, Gratitude, Adaptability",
        "Openness, Conscientiousness, Extraversion, Agreeableness, Neuroticism",
        "Confidence, Sociability, Altruism, Industriousness, Resilience",
        "Flexibility, Self-discipline, Enthusiasm, Empathy, Self-assurance"
      ],
      "answer": "Openness, Conscientiousness, Extraversion, Agreeableness, Neuroticism"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the Thematic Apperception Test (TAT), what do individuals do when presented with ambiguous pictures or scenes?",
      "options": [
        "Identify specific objects in the images",
        "Describe the images in detail",
        "Analyze the emotional content of the images",
        "Create stories about what is happening in the images",
        "Memorize the scenes for later recall"
      ],
      "answer": "Create stories about what is happening in the images"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which aspects are considered during the analysis of responses in the Rorschach test?",
      "options": [
        "Colour perception and emotional intensity",
        "Content, location, determinants, populars, and special scores",
        "Time taken to respond and specific imagery details",
        "Physical characteristics of inkblots and personal associations",
        "Familiarity with inkblot patterns and personal background information"
      ],
      "answer": "Content, location, determinants, populars, and special scores"
    },
    {
      "question": "According to the studies mentioned, which personality dimension is significantly associated with individual innovation behaviour?",
      "options": [
        "Agreeableness",
        "Conscientiousness",
        "Extraversion",
        "Emotional stability (low Neuroticism)",
        "Openness to experience"
      ],
      "answer": "Openness to experience"
    }
  ],
  "Week6": [
    {
      "question": "Which value represents a belief in personal liberties and autonomy?",
      "options": ["Compassion", "Justice", "Equality", "Integrity", "Freedom"],
      "answer": "Freedom"
    },
    {
      "question": "What role do values play in assisting employees when faced with complex decisions within an organization?",
      "options": [
        "Determining the salary structure",
        "Providing a moral compass",
        "Setting technological standards",
        "Influencing marketing strategies",
        "Directing employee hierarchies"
      ],
      "answer": "Providing a moral compass"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which source is likely to have a significant impact on an individual's values during adolescence and young adulthood?",
      "options": [
        "Family",
        "Religion and Spirituality",
        "Education",
        "Personal Reflection",
        "Peers and Social Groups"
      ],
      "answer": "Peers and Social Groups"
    },
    {
      "question": "What distinguishes terminal values from instrumental values in the Rokeach Value Survey?",
      "options": [
        "Terminal values are cultural, while instrumental values are personal.",
        "Terminal values are specific, while instrumental values are abstract.",
        "Terminal values are ultimate life goals, while instrumental values are preferred modes of behaviour.",
        "Terminal values guide behaviour, while instrumental values represent end-states.",
        "Terminal values are ethical principles, while instrumental values are societal norms."
      ],
      "answer": "Terminal values are ultimate life goals, while instrumental values are preferred modes of behaviour."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which cultural characteristic is associated with High Power Distance cultures?",
      "options": [
        "Emphasis on equality and open communication.",
        "Valuing individual goals and autonomy.",
        "Respect for hierarchy and authority.",
        "Preference for explicit verbal communication.",
        "Embrace of change, progress, and innovation."
      ],
      "answer": "Respect for hierarchy and authority."
    },
    {
      "question": "In which type of culture is explicit verbal communication highly valued?",
      "options": [
        "High-Context Cultures",
        "Individualistic Cultures",
        "Polychronic Cultures",
        "Tradition-oriented Cultures",
        "Collectivistic Cultures"
      ],
      "answer": "Individualistic Cultures"
    },
    {
      "question": "What constitutes an essential aspect of Person-Job Fit (PJ Fit)?",
      "options": [
        "Alignment between personal values and organizational culture.",
        "Compatibility between individual skills and the specific job requirements.",
        "Development of job crafting techniques.",
        "Adherence to organizational hierarchy and authority.",
        "Prioritizing collectivist cultures over individualistic cultures."
      ],
      "answer": "Compatibility between individual skills and the specific job requirements."
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a potential outcome of poor person-job fit within an organization?",
      "options": [
        "Enhanced organizational commitment",
        "Increased employee motivation",
        "Improved team dynamics",
        "Decreased job satisfaction",
        "Higher levels of innovation"
      ],
      "answer": "Decreased job satisfaction"
    },
    {
      "question": "Person-organization fit (PO fit) primarily focuses on the alignment between:",
      "options": [
        "Personal ambitions and organizational goals",
        "Individual values, goals, and organizational values, goals, and culture",
        "Workplace skills and personal development",
        "Job preferences and salary expectations",
        "Team dynamics and employee autonomy"
      ],
      "answer": "Individual values, goals, and organizational values, goals, and culture"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the context of person-organization fit and career decision making, what influence does a perceived intolerant macro-culture have on employees?",
      "options": [
        "Encourages seeking promotion or lateral moves within the organization",
        "Decreases stress and enhances self-efficacy",
        "Facilitates adapting to incongruent gender-related behaviours",
        "Discourages any career progression within the organization",
        "Promotes an environment of diverse gender-related behaviours"
      ],
      "answer": "Discourages any career progression within the organization"
    }
  ],
  "Week7": [
    {
      "question": "What are the potential benefits of implementing job rotation in organizations?",
      "options": [
        "Decreased boredom, increased motivation, enhanced understanding of work contribution",
        "Increased turnover rates, reduced employee satisfaction, decreased organizational performance",
        "Limited skill range, decreased adaptability to changes, reduced organizational performance",
        "Increased workplace conflicts, higher absenteeism, decreased productivity",
        "Enhanced job specialization, reduced training costs, increased organizational rigidity"
      ],
      "answer": "Decreased boredom, increased motivation, enhanced understanding of work contribution"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which statement accurately describes the impact of job enrichment on employee satisfaction?",
      "options": [
        "Job enrichment consistently leads to decreased employee satisfaction.",
        "Job enrichment primarily benefits employees in lower-level positions.",
        "Job enrichment may lead to increased job satisfaction, especially when the tasks are challenging.",
        "Job enrichment is irrelevant to employee satisfaction as it primarily focuses on organizational performance.",
        "Job enrichment often results in increased employee turnover due to higher job demands."
      ],
      "answer": "Job enrichment may lead to increased job satisfaction, especially when the tasks are challenging."
    },
    {
      "question": "How does job design influence employee motivation and performance?",
      "options": [
        "Job design has no impact on employee motivation and performance.",
        "Well-designed jobs typically lead to decreased employee motivation and performance.",
        "Poorly designed jobs often result in increased employee motivation and performance.",
        "Job design directly affects employee motivation and performance by shaping task characteristics.",
        "Employee motivation and performance are solely determined by external factors unrelated to job design."
      ],
      "answer": "Job design directly affects employee motivation and performance by shaping task characteristics."
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the primary focus of the Job Characteristics Model (JCM)?",
      "options": [
        "The Job Characteristics Model primarily focuses on organizational structure and hierarchy.",
        "The Job Characteristics Model aims to reduce employee autonomy and decision-making.",
        "The Job Characteristics Model emphasizes external motivators such as rewards and punishments.",
        "The Job Characteristics Model seeks to identify key job dimensions that affect employee motivation and performance.",
        "The Job Characteristics Model is primarily concerned with employee personality traits and preferences."
      ],
      "answer": "The Job Characteristics Model seeks to identify key job dimensions that affect employee motivation and performance."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a characteristic of a job with high task identity?",
      "options": [
        "High task identity means that employees have limited control over the completion of their tasks.",
        "High task identity implies that tasks are fragmented and disconnected from the overall objective.",
        "High task identity allows employees to see the results of their efforts from start to finish.",
        "High task identity indicates that employees have minimal involvement in decision-making processes.",
        "High task identity often leads to decreased job satisfaction due to increased workload."
      ],
      "answer": "High task identity allows employees to see the results of their efforts from start to finish."
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the significance of job crafting in the context of employee engagement?",
      "options": [
        "Job crafting has no impact on employee engagement as it is solely focused on task completion.",
        "Job crafting allows employees to customize their job roles and responsibilities, leading to increased engagement.",
        "Job crafting primarily involves decreasing job autonomy to improve employee engagement.",
        "Job crafting is only relevant in high-stress work environments.",
        "Job crafting is a management technique aimed at reducing employee engagement to lower turnover rates."
      ],
      "answer": "Job crafting allows employees to customize their job roles and responsibilities, leading to increased engagement."
    },
    {
      "question": "How does job rotation contribute to employee development?",
      "options": [
        "Job rotation primarily leads to decreased employee development opportunities.",
        "Job rotation allows employees to specialize in a narrow range of tasks, limiting their development.",
        "Job rotation enhances employee development by exposing them to various roles and responsibilities.",
        "Job rotation isolates employees from learning opportunities within the organization.",
        "Job rotation is irrelevant to employee development as it only focuses on organizational needs."
      ],
      "answer": "Job rotation enhances employee development by exposing them to various roles and responsibilities."
    },
    {
      "question": "What role does job enlargement play in enhancing employee motivation?",
      "options": [
        "Job enlargement reduces employee motivation by increasing job complexity.",
        "Job enlargement has no impact on employee motivation as it primarily focuses on organizational efficiency.",
        "Job enlargement enhances employee motivation by increasing the variety of tasks within a job.",
        "Job enlargement decreases employee motivation by narrowing the scope of tasks.",
        "Job enlargement isolates employees from challenging tasks, reducing motivation."
      ],
      "answer": "Job enlargement enhances employee motivation by increasing the variety of tasks within a job."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a potential drawback of job enrichment?",
      "options": [
        "Job enrichment increases employee motivation and job satisfaction.",
        "Job enrichment leads to decreased employee autonomy and control.",
        "Job enrichment may result in increased stress and job burnout.",
        "Job enrichment has no impact on employee performance.",
        "Job enrichment allows employees to specialize in a narrow range of tasks."
      ],
      "answer": "Job enrichment may result in increased stress and job burnout."
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the primary goal of flexible work arrangements?",
      "options": [
        "The primary goal of flexible work arrangements is to decrease employee autonomy.",
        "The primary goal of flexible work arrangements is to increase workplace conflicts.",
        "The primary goal of flexible work arrangements is to limit employee access to work-life balance.",
        "The primary goal of flexible work arrangements is to provide employees with greater control over their work schedules.",
        "The primary goal of flexible work arrangements is to increase employee turnover rates."
      ],
      "answer": "The primary goal of flexible work arrangements is to provide employees with greater control over their work schedules."
    }
  ],
  "Week8": [
    {
      "question": "What are the strengths associated with implementing job rotation in organizations?",
      "options": [
        "Decreased motivation, limited skill development, inflexible scheduling",
        "Increased boredom, limited understanding of work contribution, reduced organizational performance",
        "Reduced flexibility, increased layoffs, reduced job vacancies",
        "Reduced boredom, increased motivation, enhanced understanding of work contribution",
        "Limited skill range, decreased adaptability to changes, reduced organizational performance"
      ],
      "answer": "Reduced boredom, increased motivation, enhanced understanding of work contribution"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which statement accurately describes the impact of job enlargement on employee satisfaction and commitment?",
      "options": [
        "Job enlargement consistently leads to increased employee satisfaction and commitment.",
        "Enlarged jobs often reduce efficiency but always enhance employee satisfaction.",
        "Downsizing and job enlargement typically result in higher employee satisfaction and commitment.",
        "Job enlargement may not necessarily improve employee satisfaction and commitment, especially in contexts like downsizing.",
        "Enlarging jobs leads to decreased anxiety and higher levels of employee commitment."
      ],
      "answer": "Job enlargement may not necessarily improve employee satisfaction and commitment, especially in contexts like downsizing."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do cultural differences impact the acceptance of employee involvement programs?",
      "options": [
        "All cultures universally accept and readily adopt employee involvement programs.",
        "High power-distance cultures like India embrace employee involvement initiatives more than low power-distance cultures.",
        "Cultural differences have no bearing on the acceptance of employee involvement programs.",
        "Traditional values have no impact on the effectiveness of participative decision-making.",
        "Chinese workers are uniformly satisfied with participative management regardless of cultural values."
      ],
      "answer": "High power-distance cultures like India embrace employee involvement initiatives more than low power-distance cultures."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which factors are crucial for the success of participative management initiatives?",
      "options": [
        "Employee hierarchy and positional authority",
        "Disengagement from relevant issues and low competence",
        "Lack of trust and confidence among team members",
        "Relevant engagement, employee competence, and mutual trust",
        "Excessive decision-making power vested solely in superiors"
      ],
      "answer": "Relevant engagement, employee competence, and mutual trust"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a key benefit of motivation strategies in relation to employee retention?",
      "options": [
        "Decreased employee productivity",
        "Increased workplace conflicts",
        "Higher turnover rates",
        "Reduced satisfaction and commitment",
        "Greater likelihood of retaining top talent"
      ],
      "answer": "Greater likelihood of retaining top talent"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are some of the claimed benefits associated with the implementation of flexitime?",
      "options": [
        "Increased workplace conflicts and hostility towards management",
        "Rise in traffic congestion around work sites",
        "Higher overtime expenses and tardiness",
        "Reduced absenteeism and increased productivity",
        "Decreased autonomy and responsibility for employees"
      ],
      "answer": "Reduced absenteeism and increased productivity"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a potential advantage of membership and seniority-based rewards?",
      "options": [
        "Directly motivating job performance",
        "Encouraging poor performers to seek more suitable jobs",
        "Easily attracting good performers to better-paying jobs",
        "Creating a work culture valued by Millennials and Gen Z employees",
        "Discouraging employees from quitting due to deferred bonuses"
      ],
      "answer": "Discouraging employees from quitting due to deferred bonuses"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does organizational justice primarily encompass?",
      "options": [
        "Employee productivity and engagement",
        "The organizational structure and hierarchy",
        "Perceived fairness in policies, procedures, and outcomes",
        "The financial resources allocated to employees",
        "Workplace diversity and inclusion initiatives"
      ],
      "answer": "Perceived fairness in policies, procedures, and outcomes"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the primary focus of procedural justice in decision-making?",
      "options": [
        "Determining the ultimate outcome of a decision.",
        "Establishing the criteria for fair promotions.",
        "Addressing the perceived fairness of the decision-making process.",
        "Ensuring complete equality in every decision.",
        "Providing preferential treatment based on gender and race."
      ],
      "answer": "Addressing the perceived fairness of the decision-making process."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which statement best characterizes self-monitoring in the context of performance improvement?",
      "options": [
        "It primarily benefits employees in outdoor jobs such as landscaping.",
        "Self-monitoring relies solely on immediate and observable feedback from the job.",
        "All individuals are inherently capable of effectively self-monitoring their work progress.",
        "Feedback mechanisms need to be established for individuals unable to observe their work output easily.",
        "Self-monitoring is ineffective without frequent managerial intervention."
      ],
      "answer": "Feedback mechanisms need to be established for individuals unable to observe their work output easily."
    }
  ],
  "Week9": [
    {
      "question": "What are the key components of learning?",
      "options": [
        "Observation, experimentation, and practice",
        "Comprehension, application, retention, and transfer",
        "Prior knowledge, motivation, and feedback",
        "Interaction with the environment and formal education",
        "Dynamic process and lifelong acquisition of skills"
      ],
      "answer": "Comprehension, application, retention, and transfer"
    },
    {
      "question": "How does implicit knowledge differ from explicit knowledge?",
      "options": [
        "Implicit knowledge relies on demonstration and imitation.",
        "Explicit knowledge cannot be expressed verbally.",
        "Implicit knowledge is context-independent and abstract.",
        "Explicit knowledge is solely individualistic in nature.",
        "Implicit knowledge is easily shared and conveyed linguistically."
      ],
      "answer": "Implicit knowledge relies on demonstration and imitation."
    },
    {
      "question": "According to the passage, which statement accurately characterizes learning from novelty?",
      "options": [
        "Novel tasks inhibit learning potential due to their complexity.",
        "Experience in routine tasks does not contribute to learning.",
        "Efficient reading involves conscious control of perceptual operations.",
        "Learning progresses from familiarity to detail in a novice-to-expert sequence.",
        "Tacit knowledge has no impact on instinctive action in complex situations."
      ],
      "answer": "Learning progresses from familiarity to detail in a novice-to-expert sequence."
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a key element of experiential learning?",
      "options": [
        "Passive engagement with the environment",
        "A linear progression from reflection to experimentation",
        "Avoidance of theories and reflections on experiences",
        "Preference for one specific step among the learning phases",
        "Engagement, reflection, theorizing, and experimentation as integral steps"
      ],
      "answer": "Engagement, reflection, theorizing, and experimentation as integral steps"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the conditioned stimulus (CS) in Pavlov's classical conditioning experiment with the dogs?",
      "options": [
        "Meat powder",
        "Salivation",
        "Surgical procedure",
        "Bell",
        "Dog"
      ],
      "answer": "Bell"
    },
    {
      "question": "In classical conditioning, what is the conditioned response (CR) observed in Pavlov's experiment when the bell is rung alone?",
      "options": [
        "Salivation",
        "Dog's behaviour",
        "Surgical response",
        "Meat powder",
        "Neutral stimulus"
      ],
      "answer": "Salivation"
    },
    {
      "question": "According to Social Learning Theory, which of the following is crucial for learning through observation and modeling?",
      "options": [
        "Punishment",
        "Genetic predisposition",
        "Reinforcement",
        "Imitation",
        "Classical conditioning"
      ],
      "answer": "Imitation"
    },
    {
      "question": "According to Albert Bandura's self-efficacy theory, which of the following best defines self-efficacy?",
      "options": [
        "Belief in one's ability to succeed in specific situations",
        "Confidence in one's physical appearance",
        "Trust in external validation from others",
        "Perception of overall intelligence",
        "Willingness to conform to societal norms"
      ],
      "answer": "Belief in one's ability to succeed in specific situations"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is one of the shortcomings associated with traditional pay systems?",
      "options": [
        "Direct impact on employee performance",
        "Effective reinforcement for all behaviours",
        "Consistent improvement in employee satisfaction",
        "Reinforcement limited to pay check receipt",
        "Enhancement of supervisory feedback"
      ],
      "answer": "Reinforcement limited to pay check receipt"
    },
    {
      "question": "What did a comprehensive review of surveys find regarding the value employees place on various rewards?",
      "options": [
        "Financial rewards were considered most valuable across all surveys",
        "Personalized recognition from managers was ranked lowest among rewards",
        "Nonfinancial rewards were ranked higher than financial ones by employees",
        "Employees rarely prioritize recognition as an important reward",
        "Managers rarely provide any form of recognition to employees"
      ],
      "answer": "Nonfinancial rewards were ranked higher than financial ones by employees"
    }
  ],
  "Week10": [
    {
      "question": "Creativity and innovation are different in the way that:",
      "options": [
        "Innovation has value but creativity doesn’t",
        "Creativity is possessed by artists and innovation by scientists",
        "Creativity is related to idea generation and innovation is about implementation",
        "Creativity is individual generated and innovation is team generated",
        "Creativity is not required in organizations but innovation is required"
      ],
      "answer": "Creativity is related to idea generation and innovation is about implementation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Creativity is positively related to:",
      "options": [
        "Divergent thinking",
        "Convergent thinking",
        "Mental set",
        "Attitudinal change",
        "Deductive reasoning"
      ],
      "answer": "Divergent thinking"
    },
    {
      "question": "The stages of creativity are in which of the following order?",
      "options": [
        "Incubation, preparation, insight, illumination, verification",
        "Preparation, incubation, insight, verification, implementation",
        "Preparation, insight, incubation, illumination, verification",
        "Insight, verification, preparation, incubation, insight",
        "Incubation, preparation, verification, insight, implementation"
      ],
      "answer": "Preparation, incubation, insight, verification, implementation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following, based on evidence, is NOT characteristic of creative people?",
      "options": [
        "Subject-knowledge",
        "Intelligence to synthesize information",
        "A cluster of charming traits",
        "Values that support independent imagination",
        "Persistence in the face of resistance"
      ],
      "answer": "A cluster of charming traits"
    },
    {
      "question": "Repeated tests for differences between the desired outcome and what currently exists is called __________.",
      "options": [
        "Problem analysis",
        "Mental set",
        "Functional fixedness",
        "Means-end analysis",
        "Implementation"
      ],
      "answer": "Means-end analysis"
    },
    {
      "question": "Cognitive complexity refers to:",
      "options": [
        "Reframing the problem in a unique way and generating different approaches to the issue",
        "The ability to produce responses that are based primarily on knowledge and logic",
        "Preference for elaborate, intricate, and complex stimuli and thinking patterns",
        "Redefining the problem and revisiting old projects after a gap of some time",
        "Ranges from art classes to impromptu storytelling and acting"
      ],
      "answer": "Preference for elaborate, intricate, and complex stimuli and thinking patterns"
    },
    {
      "question": "Positive organizational behaviour is the application of positive oriented human resource strengths and psychological capacities that can be _______, ________, and effectively managed for performance improvement in today’s workplace?",
      "options": [
        "Referred, developed",
        "Traced, protected",
        "Designed, developed",
        "Informed, practised",
        "Measured, developed"
      ],
      "answer": "Measured, developed"
    },
    {
      "question": "Psychological capital is a higher-order core factor made up of?",
      "options": [
        "Efficacy, hope, optimism, resiliency",
        "Hope, optimism, resistance, intelligence",
        "Personality, efficiency, optimism, responsiveness",
        "Personality, honor, optimism, efficiency",
        "Effectiveness, hope, optimism, resiliency"
      ],
      "answer": "Efficacy, hope, optimism, resiliency"
    },
    {
      "question": "One of the levels of positive psychology is:",
      "options": [
        "Suppressed individual traits",
        "Suppressing one’s opinions",
        "Valued subjective experiences",
        "Personality development",
        "Attitudinal change"
      ],
      "answer": "Valued subjective experiences"
    },
    {
      "question": "Mindfulness is related to wellbeing because it helps in:",
      "options": [
        "Shared mental models",
        "Resistance",
        "Recall",
        "Performance buffering",
        "Resilience"
      ],
      "answer": "Resilience"
    }
  ],
  "Week11": [
    {
      "question": "Which of the following best defines knowledge?",
      "options": [
        "The ability to memorize facts",
        "Information acquired through learning and experience",
        "Natural talent or innate abilities",
        "The capability to solve complex mathematical problems",
        "Genetic predispositions and inherited traits"
      ],
      "answer": "Information acquired through learning and experience"
    },
    {
      "question": "According to the explicit knowledge approach, what are the primary methods for disseminating knowledge assets within an organization?",
      "options": [
        "Oral communication and informal meetings",
        "Sharing experiences and tacit knowledge",
        "Documents, standard operating procedures, and manuals",
        "In-person training sessions only",
        "Individuals cannot articulate their knowledge under any circumstances"
      ],
      "answer": "Documents, standard operating procedures, and manuals"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statements aligns with the concept of knowledge hiding, as mentioned in the text?",
      "options": [
        "Hiding knowledge is always considered a negative behaviour by managers.",
        "Providing partial information is considered a form of deception in knowledge hiding.",
        "Knowledge hiding may be motivated by positive intentions such as protecting confidentiality or third-party interests.",
        "All forms of knowledge withholding involve deliberate deception.",
        "Knowledge hiding is primarily driven by the intent to dominate within the workplace hierarchy"
      ],
      "answer": "Knowledge hiding may be motivated by positive intentions such as protecting confidentiality or third-party interests."
    },
    {
      "question": "What distinguishes knowledge hiding from deception according to the text?",
      "options": [
        "Knowledge hiding always involves intentional deception.",
        "Deception is always involved in knowledge hiding.",
        "Knowledge hiding may involve intentional concealment without deception.",
        "Deception and knowledge hiding are interchangeable terms.",
        "Knowledge hiding is inherently a positive behaviour without any deceptive aspects."
      ],
      "answer": "Knowledge hiding may involve intentional concealment without deception."
    },
    {
      "question": "What is suggested regarding employees' knowledge hiding behaviour in the organizational context?",
      "options": [
        "Employees in organizations with strong knowledge sharing climates tend to engage more in evasive hiding.",
        "Organizational climate has no influence on any type of knowledge hiding behaviour.",
        "Employees in organizations with stronger knowledge sharing climates are less likely to engage in evasive knowledge hiding.",
        "All types of knowledge hiding behaviours are positively influenced by a strong knowledge sharing climate.",
        "An organization's knowledge sharing climate impacts various forms of knowledge hiding behaviours differently."
      ],
      "answer": "Employees in organizations with stronger knowledge sharing climates are less likely to engage in evasive knowledge hiding."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which factor significantly influences the choice of evasive hiding in knowledge withholding, according to the findings?",
      "options": [
        "The level of trust between coworkers.",
        "Complexity of the requested knowledge.",
        "Job relevance of the knowledge requested.",
        "Organizational climate and policies.",
        "Personal motivation of the requester."
      ],
      "answer": "Complexity of the requested knowledge."
    },
    {
      "question": "What concept highlights the coexistence of contradictory yet interdependent cooperative and competitive behaviours, as mentioned in the context of knowledge sharing and hiding?",
      "options": [
        "Collaboration effect",
        "Knowledge convergence",
        "Coopetition",
        "Paradoxical exchange",
        "Duality of interaction"
      ],
      "answer": "Coopetition"
    },
    {
      "question": "In what scenario does the interplay between knowledge sharing and hiding behaviours generate a positive outcome regarding the impression of the sharer, as highlighted in the text?",
      "options": [
        "When employees share all information openly to reduce competitive pressure.",
        "When knowledge hiding is perceived as entirely destructive by the staff.",
        "In reactive knowledge sharing, where some information is intentionally hidden, but the sharer still assists and maintains a positive impression.",
        "When knowledge hiding is limited to non-essential information to maintain individual advantages.",
        "When knowledge sharing is absent, allowing the sharer to maintain a superior position in the organization."
      ],
      "answer": "In reactive knowledge sharing, where some information is intentionally hidden, but the sharer still assists and maintains a positive impression."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statements best captures the importance of knowledge sharing in organizational effectiveness?",
      "options": [
        "Knowledge that is not shared significantly adds to organizational effectiveness.",
        "Prosocial behaviour primarily focuses on formal job responsibilities, not knowledge sharing.",
        "Knowledge sharing is essential for boosting organizational effectiveness and adding value.",
        "Organizational effectiveness is solely dependent on formal job responsibilities, not knowledge sharing.",
        "Knowledge sharing has a minimal impact on organizational effectiveness compared to other factors."
      ],
      "answer": "Knowledge sharing is essential for boosting organizational effectiveness and adding value."
    },
    {
      "question": "What has gained increased attention in recent studies related to knowledge-sharing behaviour?",
      "options": [
        "The nature of knowledge and opportunities to share",
        "Motivation to share knowledge within the organization",
        "Peer group support in facilitating knowledge sharing",
        "The culture of the work environment in knowledge exchange",
        "Individual characteristics influencing knowledge-sharing propensity"
      ],
      "answer": "Peer group support in facilitating knowledge sharing"
    }
  ],
  "Week12": [
    {
      "question": "Promotive voice involves?",
      "options": [
        "Expressing concerns",
        "Highlight problematic issues",
        "Constructive feedback"
      ],
      "answer": "Constructive feedback"
    },
    {
      "question": "Loyalists are employees who respond to dissatisfaction by paying less attention to quality of work. True or false?",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "answer": "False"
    },
    {
      "question": "Voice relates not just to performance evaluations but also to co-workers’ perceptions of the employee. True or False?",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "A natural inclination toward taking initiative and action is:",
      "options": [
        "Loyalty",
        "Whistleblowing",
        "Prohibitive voice",
        "Promotive voice",
        "Proactivity"
      ],
      "answer": "Proactivity"
    },
    {
      "question": "Emotions like empathic concern, empathic anger, or guilt in response to someone's suffering can lead to silence. True or false?",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "answer": "False"
    },
    {
      "question": "A form of silence where individuals choose not to speak up or share their thoughts due to concerns about potential negative consequences is called?",
      "options": [
        "Diffident silence",
        "Defensive silence",
        "Acquiescent silence",
        "Acquired silence",
        "Opportunistic silence"
      ],
      "answer": "Defensive silence"
    },
    {
      "question": "Withholding issues that are not pertinent to the goals of the team or the manager at the present time is termed as?",
      "options": [
        "Silence",
        "Strategic silence",
        "Issue relevance",
        "Issue readiness",
        "Issue timing"
      ],
      "answer": "Issue relevance"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does psychological safety involve?",
      "options": [
        "The absence of any workplace challenges or stressors.",
        "Strict adherence to rigid rules and procedures in the workplace.",
        "A focus on maintaining individual success at the expense of teamwork.",
        "Ignoring diverse perspectives and opinions to maintain harmony.",
        "Encouraging open communication"
      ],
      "answer": "Encouraging open communication"
    },
    {
      "question": "How can leaders foster psychological safety?",
      "options": [
        "Making clear why employee voice matters",
        "Giving necessary punishment for poor inputs",
        "Establishing the infallibility of the leader",
        "Inviting inputs",
        "Giving productive response"
      ],
      "answer": "i, iv and v"
    },
    {
      "question": "In a psychologically safe environment, one should always feel comfortable leaving no room for conflict. True or False?",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "answer": "False"
    }
  ]
}
